Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club, 1950s; 6 (Box 1543)
    - Note: [letter from the American Museum of Natural History to Lowell Thomas concerning an Explorers Club flag], 8
    - Note: [rear of 6.8 above], 9
    - Note: [diagram of Rock Summit?], 10
    - Note: [letter to Lowell Thomas concerning Explorers club expedition], 11
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club [includes one color photograph], 1960s; 7 (Box 1543)
    - Lowell Thomas and Edward C. Sweeney, President of The Explorers Club [circa 1966-1967], 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas and Edward C. Sweeney, President of The Explorers Club [circa 1966-1967], 1-verso
    - Dr. Walter Wood of E.C. and LT [circa 1968], 2
    - Verso: Dr. Walter Wood of E.C. and LT [circa 1968], 2-verso
    - Note: [letter from Ward Randol, Executive Director of The Explorer's Club to Lowell Thomas concerning photograph 7.2], 3
    - [left to right: unidentified man, Lowell Thomas, Walter Wood; Night of Exploration Dinner, December 1968], 4
    - [left to right: Lowell Thomas, Walter Wood; Night of Exploration Dinner, December 1968], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas, left, Walter Wood, right], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and an unidentified man], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas at the banquet table], 8
    - Note: [letter from Serge A. Korff of The Explorer's Club to Lowell Thomas concerning photograph 7.8], 9
    - President Richard M. Nixon; Left to right: Explorer Mark Van Wagoner and President Nixon, 10
    - Verso: President Richard M. Nixon; Left to right: Explorer Mark Van Wagoner and President Nixon, 10-verso
    - (left to right) Sir Edmund Hillary, Wernher von Braun, Finn Ronne and Lowell Thomas enjoy an informal moment before the dinner [1962], 11
    - Note: [left to right] Sir Edmund Hillary, Wernher von Braun, Finn Ronne and Lowell Thomas enjoy an informal moment before the dinner [1962], 12
    - Caption: Here's to you, Finn! Lowell Thomas, 13
    - (left to right) Sir Edmund Hillary, Wernher von Braun, Finn Ronne and Lowell Thomas enjoy an informal moment before the dinner [1962][4 copies], 14
    - Caption: Prime Crew of Second Manned Apollo Mission: James A. Lovell, Jr., William A. Andersm Frank Borman, 15
    - Verso: NASA, National Aeronautics and Space Administration: SECOND MANNED APOLLO CREW - The prime crew members of Apollo 8 are (left to right), 15-verso
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (Tenzing Norgay) [Tenzing Norkey], 1960s; 8 (Box 1543)
    - [Tenzing Norkey], 1
    - [Tenzing Norkey], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and The Explorers Club], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas and other members of The Explorers Club], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with members of The Explorers Club], 5
    - [Tenzing Norkey giving a speech], 6
    - [Tenzing Norkey delivering a speech at The Explorers Club], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with Tenzing Norkey], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas, Tenzing Norkey, and two other members of The Explorer Club ], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas, Tenzing Norkey, and other members of The Explorer Club], 10
    - [Tenzing Norkey talking with an Indian woman], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas, Tenzing Norkey (on left), and four other memebers of The Explorers Club], 12
    - [Tenzing Norkey (on left) and Lowell Thomas with five other memebers of The Explorers Club], 13
    - [Tenzing Norkey with a palte of food at the buffet], 14
    - [Guests on line for the buffet], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas getting food from the buffet], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas with two plates of food on the buffet line], 17
    - [Man and woman getting food at the buffet], 18
    - [Tenzing Norkey (on right) and another member of The Explorers Club], 19
    - [Tenzing Norkey (on left) sitting with an Indian woman], 20
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting at the dinner table, talking with other members of The Explorers Club], 21
    - [Banquet tables at an Explorers Club event], 22
    - [Lowell Thomas's table at The Explorers Club formal dinner], 23
    - [Lowell Thomas at a banquet with other members of the Explorers Club], 24
    - [Lowell Thomas and two other guests at The Explorers Club banquet], 25
    - [Lowell Thomas and two unidentified men], 26
    - [Lowell Thomas and other members of The Explorers Club], 27
    - [Caption: Tenzing Norkey at Everest summit with flags of Britain and India--an illustration from LOWELL THOMAS' BOOK OF THE HIGH MOUNTAINS published by Julian Messner (?), Inc. Please Credit Information Service of India], 28
    - [Caption: The Burma Road, photographed by the U.S. Army Signal Corps--an illustration from LOWELL THOMAS' BOOK OF THE HIGH MOUNTAINS published by Julian Messner (?), Inc. Please credit Monkmeyer], 29
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (awarding The Explorers Medal), 1960 April 26; 9 (Box 1543)
    - EXPLORERS HONOR HOOVER; Former President Herbert Hoover, center, is honored by The Explorers Club before the Night of Exploration Dinner at NY's Waldorf Astoria Hotel April 26th. Presenting The Explorers Club medal to the former President to his achievements in exploration and his outstanding public service is Lowell Thomas, toastmaster. At left is Dr. Charles B. Hitchcock, President of the club. Among the explorations carried out by Mr. Hoover were those he made in his younger days as a mining and petroleum engineer, 1
    - Note: EXPLORERS HONOR HOOVER; Former President Herbert Hoover, center, is honored by The Explorers Club before the Night of Exploration Dinner at NY's Waldorf Astoria Hotel April 26th. Presenting The Explorers Club medal to the former President to his achievements in exploration and his outstanding public service is Lowell Thomas, toastmaster. At left is Dr. Charles B. Hitchcock, President of the club. Among the explorations carried out by Mr. Hoover were those he made in his younger days as a mining and petroleum engineer, 2
    - Herbert Hoover honored by Explorers Club, 3
    - Herbert Hoover honored by Explorers Club, 4
    - [3 copies], [Vilhjalmur Stefansson, center, is honored by The Explorers Club before the Night of Exploration Dinner at NY's Waldorf Astoria Hotel April 26th. At right is Lowell Thomas, toastmaster; at left is Dr. Charles B. Hitchcock, President of the club], 5
    - [Donald B. MacMillan, center, is honored by The Explorers Club before the Night of Exploration Dinner at NY's Waldorf Astoria Hotel April 26th. At right is Lowell Thomas, toastmaster; at left is Dr. Charles B. Hitchcock, President of the club], 6
    - [Donald B. MacMillan, center, is honored by The Explorers Club before the Night of Exploration Dinner at NY's Waldorf Astoria Hotel April 26th. At right is Lowell Thomas, toastmaster], 7
    - [4 copies], [left to right: Vilhjalmur Stefansson, Lowell Thomas, Donald B. MacMillan], 8
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (Lowell Thomas bust by sculptor Philip Kraczkowski), 1969; 10 (Box 1543)
    - [Philip Kraczkowski, left, Lowell Thomas, right], 1
    - [Philip Kraczkowski, left, Lowell Thomas, right], 2
    - [Philip Kraczkowski, left, Lowell Thomas, right], 3
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club, 1970s; 11 (Box 1543)
    - [left to right: Finn Ronne, Lowell Thomas, Thor Heyerdahl], 1
    - Note: [letter from Lowell Thomas to Bill [Mark] concerning the photographs of Thor Heyerdahl], 2
    - Note: [letter from Bill Mark to Electra [Nicks] concerning photographs], 3
    - [Thor Heyerdahl, left, Lowell Thomas, right], 4
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (The Lowell Thomas Building) [includes color photographs], 1977; 12 (Box 1543)
    - The Explorers Club - New York April 16, 1977 Dedication of the Club building as the Lowell Thomas Building Left to Right: Howell Joiner, Schmidt boy, Lowell Thomas and Carl von Hoffman. In the right edge is Richard Steel (sec. of the club.) Picture taken by Ernie Schmidt and slide sent to Howell L. Joiner, 1
    - Verso: The Explorers Club - New York April 16, 1977 Dedication of the Club building as the Lowell Thomas Building Left to Right: Howell Joiner, Schmidt boy, Lowell Thomas and Carl von Hoffman. In the right edge is Richard Steel (sec. of the club.) Picture taken by Ernie Schmidt and slide sent to Howell L. Joiner, 1-verso
    - [2 copies] April 16, 1977 Dedication of the Club building as the Lowell Thomas Building Left to Right: Howell Joiner, Schmidt boy, Lowell Thomas and Carl von Hoffman, 2
    - [2 copies] April 16, 1977 Dedication of the Club building as the Lowell Thomas Building Left to Right: Howell Joiner, Schmidt boy, Lowell Thomas and Carl von Hoffman, 3
    - Note: LT with a 95 year old explorer who was with Theo. [Theodore] Roosevelt on his River of Doubt expedition - up the Amazon. His name Carl von Hoffman: phone Explorers Club and asked the secy. for his name. Also a young potential explorer. 46 E 70th Explorers Bldg. Note: Anderson, IN., Nov. 8, 1977, Dear Lowell: Here is a print of the Lowell Thomas Building dedication. Ernie Schmidt took the picture and sent me the slide. If by chance you would like a larger print I could send you one. I trust that your Tibetan trip was all that you had hoped for. I would love to hear a report of it soon. Unfortunately, I will miss our Annual Dinner next spring due to the fact that I will be on expedition in the Sahara again. I send my regards to Marianna. Sincerely, your friend, Howell. Howell L. Joiner, 4
    - [Lowell Thomas Building?], 5
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club, circa 1960s -1970s; 13 (Box 1543)
    - [Lowell Thomas holding a microphone at an Explorers Club event], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas giving a speech at an Explorers Club event], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas on stage with other memebers of The Explorers Club], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas and others on stage at an Explorers Club event], 4
    - LT and Dr. Serge Korff, 5
    - Verso: LT and Dr. Serge Korff, 5-verso
    - Mrs. William H. Phelps (Kathy); Dr. Serge A. Korff, 6
    - Verso: Mrs. William H. Phelps (Kathy); Dr. Serge A. Korff, 6-verso
    - Van Dusen [Deusen?], far left; L.T. and Dr. Walter Wood, 7
    - Verso: Van Dusen [Deusen?], far left; L.T. and Dr. Walter Wood, 7-verso
    - Left to Right, Russell Gurnee, spelunker, Norman L. Baker, Ra I and II, navigator of Ra, Lowell Thomas, 8
    - Verso: Left to Right, Russell Gurnee, spelunker, Norman L. Baker, Ra I and II, navigator of Ra, Lowell Thomas, 8-verso
    - Col. Bernt Balchen, 9
    - Verso: Col. Bernt Balchen, 9-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and other memebers of The Explorers Club standing in front of a banner reading "Most of Outer Space"], [2 copies], 10
    - Photograph attached to note 13.12, 11
    - Note: [letter from Corwith Cramer, Jr. to Lowell Thomas concerning Marco Polo Club and Explorers Club and photographs], 12
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (Osa and Martin Johnson), undated; 14 (Box 1543)
    - A. Mr. & Mrs. Martin Johnson [14.1 & 14.2 are on the same sheet with the same Verso], 1
    - Verso: A. Mr. & Mrs. Martin Johnson; B. African interior, 1-verso
    - B. African interior [14.1 & 14.2 are on the same sheet with the same Verso], 2
    - Verso: A. Mr. & Mrs. Martin Johnson; B. African interior, 2-verso
    - Note: [letter from Ward Randol, Executive Director of The Explorer's Club to Lowell Thomas concerning photographs], 3
    - Mr. and Mrs. Johnson and the King and Queen (Africa), 4
    - Verso: Mr. and Mrs. Johnson and the King and Queen (Africa), 4-verso
    - Mrs. Johnson with rifle, 5
    - Verso: Mrs. Johnson with rifle, 5-verso
    - Mr. Johnson riding zebra, 6
    - Verso: Mr. Johnson riding zebra, 6-verso
    - Mrs. Martin Johnson, 7
    - Verso: Mrs. Martin Johnson, 7-verso
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (Carveth Wells), undated; 15 (Box 1543)
    - Bakonjo; Tribesmen who scaled the Mountains of the Moon, 1
    - Verso: Bakonjo; Tribesmen who scaled the Mountains of the Moon, 1-verso
    - [giraffe], 2
    - Left to right: John Cudahy, Carveth Wells, Martin Johnson, Dr. Barrett, 3
    - Verso: Left to right: John Cudahy, Carveth Wells, Martin Johnson, Dr. Barrett, 3-verso
    - Stetson hat in use while others use helmets; Mountains of the Moon, Explorers Club flag; Camp [?], I [Carveth Wells] am sitting on a wooden box, 4
    - Verso: Stetson hat in use while others use helmets; Mountains of the Moon, Explorers Club flag; Camp [?], I [Carveth Wells] am sitting on a wooden box, 4-verso
    - [Members of The Explorers Club at camp], 5
    - [Three men (memebers of The Explorers Club?) sitting in front of a tent], 6
    - Endless Caverns, Virginia; C. Wells second from right, 7
    - Verso: Endless Caverns, Virginia; C. Wells second from right, 7-verso
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club [includes color photographs], undated; 16 (Box 1543)
    - Carl E. Akeley in his studio AMNH [American Museum of Natural History], 1
    - Verso: Carl E. Akeley in his studio AMNH [American Museum of Natural History], 1-verso
    - Lincoln Ellsworth, 2
    - Verso: Lincoln Ellsworth, 2-verso
    - Dr. Robert Cushman [Murphy], Chairman, Bird Department, AMNH [American Museum of Natural History], 3
    - Verso: Dr. Robert Cushman [Murphy], Chairman, Bird Department, AMNH [American Museum of Natural History], 3-verso
    - Dr. and Mrs. Robert Cushman Murphy with penguin, Caswell Sound, New Zealand, 4
    - Verso: Dr. and Mrs. Robert Cushman Murphy with penguin, Caswell Sound, New Zealand, 4-verso
    - Young tree-climbing kangaroo; 1964; Hobart M. Van Deusen, 5
    - Verso: Young tree-climbing kangaroo; 1964; Hobart M. Van Deusen, 5-verso
    - 1959, T.N.G. [Territory of New Guinea?], Mt. Michael - Summit Ridge; H. M. Van Deusen, 6
    - Verso: 1959, T.N.G. [Territory of New Guinea?], Mt. Michael - Summit Ridge; H. M. Van Deusen, 6-verso
    - Hobart M. Van Deusen?, 7
    - Verso: Hobart M. Van Deusen?, 7-verso
    - [Armand Denis], 8
    - [Armand Denis], 9
    - [Portrait of a member of The Explorers Club (?)], 10
    - [Member of The Explorers Club (?) on a boat], 11
    - [Mountain and lake landscape], 12
    - [Sled dogs pulling a man through snowy terrain], 13
    - [Kids swimming in a pool], 14
    - [Member of The Explorers Club holding the Club's flag in front of an airplane], 15
    - [Members of The Explorers Club with the Club's flag], 16
    - Past Presidents, Stefansson(deceased) Chapin(dec.) Spinden(dec.) Wetmore; Eskimios on Wall Ootah + were with Peary on March to Pole, 17
    - Verso: Past Presidents, Stefansson(deceased) Chapin(dec.) Spinden(dec.) Wetmore; Eskimios on Wall Ootah + were with Peary on March to Pole, 17-verso
  - Subject files: Famous, circa 1930s - 1981; 17 (Box 1543)
    - Helen Hayes - left A. P. man in Germany for many years, Louis Lochner; at Harvard Club in [?], 1
    - Verso: Helen Hayes - left A. P. man in Germany for many years, Louis Lochner; at Harvard Club in [?], 1-verso
    - Mary Pickford Day at the Advertising Club of New York at the foot of the Stanford White staircase 1932?, 2
    - Note: Mary Pickford Day at the Advertising Club of New York at the foot of the Stanford White staircase 1932?, 3
    - Jayne Mansfield; What would be a good caption for this? I want to send one to Pat Hogan; LT reporting - hot news from the Front; LT reporting - advocate of making mts. out of molehills, 4
    - Verso: Jayne Mansfield; What would be a good caption for this? I want to send one to Pat Hogan; LT reporting - hot news from the Front; LT reporting - advocate of making mts. out of molehills, 4-verso
    - Left to right: Lowell Thomas, Son of Senator Edward Kennedy, Senator Edward Kennedy, Bertram Ames, 5
    - Verso: Left to right: Lowell Thomas, Son of Senator Edward Kennedy, Senator Edward Kennedy, Bertram Ames, 5-verso
    - Caption: Here we are, Lowell. Yucca Flat, 7:30 a.m. April 22, 1952. Shot Day. Hugh Baillie, 6
    - Verso: Hugh Baillie, Pres. of U.P., Bob Considine of I.N.S., L.T. [Lowell Thomas at center], 6-verso
    - Nelson Rockefeller [right], 7
    - Verso: Nelson Rockefeller [right], 7-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and Frank Borman], 8
    - Art Linkletter [left], 9
    - Verso: Art Linkletter [left], 9-verso
    - Julie Nixon Eisenhower and David Eisenhower with Lowell Thomas, 10
    - Julie Nixon Eisenhower and David Eisenhower with Lowell Thomas, 11
    - Verso: Julie Nixon Eisenhower and David Eisenhower with Lowell Thomas, 11-verso
    - Caption: Edgar Hoover, Banshee Lunch, April22 '72; deceased May 2-'72, 12
    - Joan Crawford; Wagner International Photos, Inc., 13
    - Verso: Joan Crawford; Wagner International Photos, Inc., 13-verso
    - Mayor [New York City] Robert F. Wagner, 14
    - Verso: Mayor [New York City] Robert F. Wagner, 14-verso
    - Caption: To Cy - All the best! Lowell Thomas, 15
    - Caption: Here's to you, Ed! Lowell Thomas, 16
    - Caption: G.A. Richard's All-American 59th Birthday Party, March 19, 1948; Lowell Thomas, captain Eddie Rickenbacker, Sid Luckman, Bo McMillan, Ernie McCoy, Ty Cobb, Frank Leahy, Father Cavanaugh, Pres. John A. Hannah, Gov. Kim Sigler, George Halas, Coach G.A. Richards, 17
    - Note: [letter to Lowell Thomas from George R. Wallace concerning photograph of explorer airplane, 1543.17.19], [PDF], 18
    - Initial flight of The Explorer, June 30,1966 - Elmira, N.Y.; Pilot - Capt. Kim Scribner; Co-Pilot - George R. Wallace [included with letter to Lowell Thomas from George R. Wallace], 19
    - Verso: Initial flight of The Explorer, June 30,1966 - Elmira, N.Y.; Pilot - Capt. Kim Scribner; Co-Pilot - George R. Wallace, 19-verso
    - Marlo Thomas Donahue; Picture taken at George Peabody Awards Luncheon sponsored by Broadcast Pioneers May 6, 1981, Hotel Pierre - New York City, 20
    - Verso: Marlo Thomas Donahue; Picture taken at George Peabody Awards Luncheon sponsored by Broadcast Pioneers May 6, 1981, Hotel Pierre - New York City, 20-verso
    - Note: [letter from James T. Chamness, M.D. to Lowell Thomas concerning photographs of his father, items 17.21 & 17.22], [PDF], 21
    - [Father of James T. Chamness], 22
    - [Father of James T. Chamness], 23
    - [Vilhjalmur Stefansson and Lowell Thomas], 24
  - Subject files: Famous, undated; 18 (Box 1543)
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with three men and a woman], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas Jr. (?) talking with a man], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man talking], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas and two other men looking at something on a piece of paper], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a man], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man talking at a punch bowl], 7
  Box 1544
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Famous First Flights [proposed photographs for use in book], 1920 - 1963; 1 (Box 1544)
    - Chapter V, after photo #11 in same chapter V, Magellans of the Air, 1
    - Verso: Chapter V, after photo #11 in same chapter V, Magellans of the Air, 1-verso
    - Chapter 16, Pix No. 3 Flight Historian Lowell Thomas, Jr., Col. Bernt Balchen and aviation publisher Wayne Parrish (left to right) demonstrate their solidarity on the objectives of the Double Pole flight., 2
    - Verso: Chapter 16, Pix No. 3 Flight Historian Lowell Thomas, Jr., Col. Bernt Balchen and aviation publisher Wayne Parrish (left to right) demonstrate their solidarity on the objectives of the Double Pole flight., 2-verso
    - Finch and Austin; Photo from TWA, John F. Kennedy International Airport - New York City, 3
    - Verso: Finch and Austin; Photo from TWA, John F. Kennedy International Airport - New York City, 3-verso
    - Capetown, South Africa - Radm. Reedy and pilots of VX-6 discuss plans for non-stop flight by two C-130's from Capetown, South Africa to McMurdo Sound, Antarctica. L/R - LCDR. R.G. Dickerson (plane commander of lead plan "18" ) Lowell Thomas (CBS News correspondent) Radm. James R. Reedy, CDR. G.R. Kelly (commanding officer VX-6, standing is LTJG D.E. Miller (navigator on "18" ); U.S. Naval Photographic Center, 4
    - Verso: Capetown, South Africa - Radm. Reedy and pilots of VX-6 discuss plans for non-stop flight by two C-130's from Capetown, South Africa to McMurdo Sound, Antarctica. L/R - LCDR. R.G. Dickerson (plane commander of lead plan "18" ) Lowell Thomas (CBS News correspondent) Radm. James R. Reedy, CDR. G.R. Kelly (commanding officer VX-6, standing is LTJG D.E. Miller (navigator on "18" ); U.S. Naval Photographic Center, 4-verso
    - [A pilot of the Famous First Flights], 5
    - L.T. at South Pole shaking hands with Rear Admiral James R. Reedy, 6
    - Verso: L.T. at South Pole shaking hands with Rear Admiral James R. Reedy, 6-verso
    - Welcome by Prime Minister- William Morris Hughes. To Parer and MacIntosh at Flemington, Melbourne, Victoria on completion of their flight from Eng. To Australia. August 1920. At Culcain, Victoria - The plane made a forced landing in a muddy paddock (after much rain) turned on its nose. They flew to Melb in another plane. "P.D." brought to Melb later for welcome; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 7
    - Verso: Welcome by Prime Minister- William Morris Hughes. To Parer and MacIntosh at Flemington, Melbourne, Victoria on completion of their flight from Eng. To Australia. August 1920. At Culcain, Victoria - The plane made a forced landing in a muddy paddock (after much rain) turned on its nose. They flew to Melb in another plane. "P.D." brought to Melb later for welcome; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 7-verso
    - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 8
    - Verso: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 8-verso
    - Hounslow Airport, England. Just before starting off on flight from England to Australia. Jan 9th 1920. Lieuts. Parer and MacIntosh; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 9
    - Verso: Hounslow Airport, England. Just before starting off on flight from England to Australia. Jan 9th 1920. Lieuts. Parer and MacIntosh; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 9-verso
    - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 10
    - Verso: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 10-verso
    - The Explorers Club flag; J. R. Eyerman Photographer, 475 - 17th Street, Santa Monica, California; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 11
    - Verso: The Explorers Club flag; J. R. Eyerman Photographer, 475 - 17th Street, Santa Monica, California; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 11-verso
    - L to R: LCDR. W.B. Kurlak, plane commander of LC-130F #148320; LCDR. R.G. Dickerson, plane commander of LC-130F #148318; Radm. James R. Reedy, commander task force 43; CDR. George R. Kelly, commanding officer of Airdevron Six: At McMurdonsound, Antarctica on completion of their historic non-stop flight from Capetown, South Africa to McMurdo; U.S. Naval Photographic Center; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 12
    - Verso: L to R: LCDR. W.B. Kurlak, plane commander of LC-130F #148320; LCDR. R.G. Dickerson, plane commander of LC-130F #148318; Radm. James R. Reedy, commander task force 43; CDR. George R. Kelly, commanding officer of Airdevron Six: At McMurdonsound, Antarctica on completion of their historic non-stop flight from Capetown, South Africa to McMurdo; U.S. Naval Photographic Center; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 12-verso
    - p. 364 September 1926 National Geographic from Admiral Byrd; Chapter VIII; Doubleday & Company, Inc., 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017, Title: Famous First Flights, 13